David Keya

davidwkeya@gmail.com • 562 306 3506 linkedin.com/in/david-keya/ • Long Beach, California https://davidkeya.com • github.com/davidkeya

Talented individual with ability to identify, process, and approve wide variety of data sets used for data/text mining, modeling, and predicting to enable informed business decisions.

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Business Analysis

 Demonstrated ability to deliver cost-effective business plans and analysis to meet challenging market demands.

Database Management

 Skilled in maintaining accurate policy data and documents within organizational systems.

Customer Service

 Instrumental in exceptional service delivery while addressing client's risk management needs and ensuring smooth conversation.

EDUCATION

Certificate Data Science & Analytics General Assembly, Los Angeles CA

Bachelor of Education Science Mathematics and PhysicsKenyatta University, Nairobi, Kenya

CERTIFICATIONS

- Statistics Specialization with Python (Probability, Inferential Statistics), Khan Academy, Coursera
- The Complete SQL Bootcamp, Udemy
- Data Science Bootcamp with Python, Udemy
- Microsoft Excel Data Analysis with Excel Pivot Tables, Udemy
- Introduction to Advanced SQL, Kaggle Learn

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Children of the Night, Los Angeles, CA Mathematics and Computer Tutor

Nov 2020 - Present

Specialized as an individual tutor by simplifying math concepts while coaching students to think critically to solve problems.

Jiffy Lube Multi-care, Long Beach, CA Assistant Service Advisor

Nov 2019 - Present

Gain comprehensive knowledge of products and services to sell and furnish available parts and over 20 service options to customers.

 Ensured effective service delivery while providing an average of 40 customers' product needs and updates throughout process.

DENSO, Long Beach, CA Junior Inventory Analyst

Jan 2018 - Nov 2019

Deployed best practices to maintain and update inventory records. Analyzed and processed data by utilizing Excel sheets. Recognized for carrying out data entry and auditing activities as per standards. Supported in warehouse management system to improve inventory operations.

Reduced inventory errors through deep data monitoring and analysis.

Teachers Service Commission, Nairobi, Kenya Sep 2010 – May 2017 High School Math and Physics Tutor

Developed and Implemented engaging effective lessons in Calculus, Pre-Calculus, Money-Management, Statistics, and Geometry.

Key Projects

- Provided sales analysis for Python Pandas and Matplotlib project while conducting data exploration of five high-level business questions and enabling forecasting future performance with over 87% accuracy.
- Devised innovative approaches to prepare 356,758 rows and 100 columns of NFL dataset for exploring 24% omitted data as well as drop values with 43% of columns within NAN values.
- Led <u>analysis</u> project to explore statistics of coronavirus pandemic.

Technical Proficiencies

Python, Git and Version Control, SQL, Pandas, Microsoft Excel, Git, Numpy, iPython Notebooks, Jupyter Notebooks.